hey everybody welcome to this a1
english listening practice video you can
use
this video to practice your listening
and comprehension as i speak before we
start
remember to subscribe to the channel
click
on the bell and follow us on instagram
you ready
[Music]
so today i'm gonna talk about the
internet this is a very relevant
topic because all of us use
the internet if you're watching this
video that means you're using the
internet the internet is a really
important invention can you imagine
your life without it i can't
so let's talk about the history
the use the positives and the negatives
of the internet the first version of the
internet was created in the 1960s
this was a prototype a prototype
is an early model of a product
so the prototype of the internet
was the early version of the internet
it was created in the us
the u.s government started this
project but that internet
wasn't the same as today's internet
the world wide web was created
in 1989. people
didn't have the internet at home until
later for example my family
started using the internet around the
year 2000
how about you when did you start
using the internet okay now let's talk
about the
benefits of the internet the internet
is one of the most important inventions
it changed the world before the internet
there were fewer ways to communicate
with people who were far away
you could call them on the phone or
you could write them a letter i remember
writing letters when i was a kid
but nowadays most people don't write
letters anymore we write emails
or we send text messages
thanks to the internet we can send
messages instantly so
communication is faster and easier
nowadays many people can have
long distance relationships because of
the internet
you can talk to your boyfriend or
girlfriend
for free using skype or other apps
for that reason it's easier to have a
long
distance relationship nowadays it's
still
hard of course but the internet
makes it a little easier another
benefit of the internet is the
information
it contains you can find anything
and everything on the internet if you
want to learn about something
it's super easy you just need to
search for that subject on the internet
there are so many useful resources
online okay now let's talk about
some of the negative effects of the
internet
for example there's a lot of bad
content on the internet not everything
is
good and helpful there are a lot of
things
online that we should avoid
parents need to be careful because
children can find anything online
another negative thing is that people
spend
a lot of time on the internet
many of us spend hours and hours
every day on the computer we
should spend more time outside
but we don't we're addicted to the
internet
one other negative effect of the
is that our relationships can get
worse now it's less common
to talk to people in person we usually
talk to people online this means
that many children don't learn good
communication
skills and sometimes people can get in
arguments online people often
argue on facebook or other social media
apps alright let me teach you a few
vocabulary words
related to the internet we use the
phrase
login or log into when we
enter into an account like facebook
and we use the phrase log out when we
exit so you can say i logged into
facebook
or i logged out of facebook now
let's look at the word username this
is the name that you use to log into
an account you use your username
and password to log in for example
my username is englishteacher123
lastly let's look at the word browser
a browser is what you use to open
web pages some examples of browsers
are safari and google chrome
okay now i'm going to ask you some
questions about the video to see
if you understood write your answers
in a comment down below number one
when was the world wide web invented
number two what is one app you can
use to talk to people far away
and number three what is one negative
effect of the internet alright remember
to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram
for more english tips and lessons i'll
see you next time
[Music]
you